<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on पुराणे विश्वासटिप्पणयः</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on पुराणे विश्वासटिप्पणयः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian rAmAyaNa</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-13_mongolian-ramayana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-13_mongolian-ramayana/</guid>
      <description>The vaiShNava journeying beyond the hallowed Oddiyana pITha, where he had performed the worship of vArAhI, and karNamoTini, arrived at the oasis of Khotan. Having obtained several manuscripts of various Indic texts in Central Asia he moved further ahead on horse to make a rendezvous with his Mongolian guide. Having mounted a fresh horse and penetrated deep into the steppes they arrived after a week at the remote outposts of what was once the organizing ground of the great Oirat emperors, Esen Taiji and Amasanji Taiji.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some words on “para-Rāmāyāṇa-s”-I</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2016-08-12_some-words-on-para-ramayaNa-s-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2016-08-12_some-words-on-para-ramayaNa-s-i/</guid>
      <description>I use the hybrid Greek-Sanskrit word para-rāmāyāṇa for all rāma-kathā-s other than that of Vālmīki. These span a great diversity of literature going back to relatively early times in Indo-Aryan tradition. Lots of people have said a lot of things on this matter and we are hardly going to review any of that here. The Rāmāyaṇa itself is enigmatic in some ways. There is no allusion to the main characters of the epic in the Vedic corpus just like the central pāṇḍu heroes of the Mahābhārata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rāmāyaṇa and a para-rāmāyaṇa in numbers-I: epic as religion</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2017-02-12_the-ramayana-and-a-para-ramayana-in-numbers-i-epic-as-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2017-02-12_the-ramayana-and-a-para-ramayana-in-numbers-i-epic-as-religion/</guid>
      <description>(मानसतरङ्गिणीकृता लिखितम्। अत्र सौकर्याय रक्षितम्।)
This note may be read as part of our studies on the Rāmāyaṇa and para-Rāmāyaṇa-s of which an earlier part is presented here.
A study of the epic in Indo-European tradition suggests that there were two registers of the old Indo-European religion. While today both of them survive together with any vigor only among the Hindus, until not too long ago these registers showed some survival even among their Iranian cousins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ऐन्द्रता</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/aindra-epic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/rAmAyaNam/meta/MT_lekhAH/aindra-epic/</guid>
      <description>The below comments by the revered mAnasatarangiNIkAra throw light on the connection between niyoga and ashvamedha – with particular reference to the birth of rAma. Also note ancillary remarks about how the epics can be interpreted as mirrors of the shruti; and how besides that, they must be read at many levels. And note the (very credible) theory that the current rAmAyaNa is a vaiShNava recasting of an aindra epic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>