<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on पुराणे विश्वासटिप्पण्यः</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on पुराणे विश्वासटिप्पण्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>draupadi ammAL and chunItan</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-22_draupadi-ammal-and-chunitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-05-22_draupadi-ammal-and-chunitan/</guid>
      <description>A sub-set of the smarta brahmins of Gingee, Melaccheri Kadu and parts of the modern Telugu country upwards of Kalahasti, usually belonging to the great sect of bR^ihatcharaNaM or rarely the vaDamas (northerners), are called pAratiyAr-s. There are other pAratiyAr-s belonging the middle caste vELALar-s. Both of them are associated with the draupadi ammAL temples of the region, whose many patrons are vanniyar-s. The vanniyar-s are described by some as shUdra or avarNa, but their and internal beliefs point to the possibility that they were actually vahni-kula rAjaputra-s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mid-night thoughts on Pauranic testimony</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-10_mid-night-thoughts-on-pauranic-testimony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-10_mid-night-thoughts-on-pauranic-testimony/</guid>
      <description>“Hindus have no historical sense”; “India is a cul de sac”; “upaniShads and the buddha were contemporaneous and had Greek influence”. I heard all this gibberish and more from my school textbooks and leftist colleagues. I had long back silently noticed the precision with which Hindus recorded dates on their stone and copper plate inscriptions, be it Sanskrit or a regional dialect. This immediately brought home to me in a flash that the white scholars and their fellow-travellers were looking for Hindu historicity in the wrong places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The jaina view</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-24_the-jaina-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-24_the-jaina-view/</guid>
      <description>The jainas possess some interesting divergent variants of the canonical Indo-Aryan myths. The harivaMsha of jinasena and the triShaShThisalakapuruSha charita of hemachandra is a rather rich source for such mythic material. The jaina view postulated the existance of 63 salakapuruShas or notable figures who are like spokes in the wheel of time. Not unexpectedly the 63 includes the 24 tirthankaras. Other than these there are 12 chakravartins who start with the great bhArata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pauranic testimony and some time lines in Hindu tradition</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-11_the-pauranic-testimony-and-some-time-lines-in-hindu-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-11_the-pauranic-testimony-and-some-time-lines-in-hindu-tradition/</guid>
      <description>I believe that despite all the noise on the topics the purANas are at this point more enlightening on certain points than all the archaeology of the Indian subcontinent. In fact it appears important that the future archaeological studies in India, if they occur at all, must keep in the mind the Pauranic timelines for poorly known Hindu dynasties. At the outset I must make it clear that some well-known dates contested recently by Hindu historical revisionists are indeed correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The temple of irAvAn</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-08_the-temple-of-iravan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/purANam/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-06-08_the-temple-of-iravan/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the temples of draupadi ammAL there are a cluster of temples of irAvAn close to the point the where my paternal ancestor first immigrated to the Dravida country. Our clanswoman had obtained a detailed account of the itihAsa of irAvAn from one of the most learned smArta bhAratiyAr-s of that locality whose clan was associated with that of our ancestors for a while. Of course the smArta narrative differs quite drastically from the narratives of the tevar and other tamil pAratiyAr-s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>